<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analyses on Diversity ∙ Supplementary Materials</title>
    <link>/analyses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analyses on Diversity ∙ Supplementary Materials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/analyses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 1</title>
      <link>/analyses/hypothesis1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/hypothesis1/</guid>
      <description>Over the past several years, social scientists have noted that the discourse of “diversity” is expanding in use across various social contexts (Berrey 2015). In this project, we are interested in measuring how often diversity and its various metonyms are mentioned in biomedical research over the three decades (1990-2017). Our first working hypothesis is that:
 The use of the term ‘diversity’ and its related terminology has increased in biomedical abstracts since 1990.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 2</title>
      <link>/analyses/hypothesis2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/hypothesis2/</guid>
      <description>While our first set of analyses established that “diversity” is increasing modestly in the biomedical literature, we also wanted to account for how terminology related to population testing has changed over time. Fujimura and Rajagopalan’s (2011) have suggested that researchers now use biogeographic and genetic ancestry terms more often than race and ethnicity in their studies. Relatedly, Panofsky and Bliss (2017) have found that racial and ethnic terms (including those within the US Census and OMB Directive 15 labeling schema) have been replaced by more general biogeographic terms such continental, national, and directional terminology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 3</title>
      <link>/analyses/hypothesis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/hypothesis3/</guid>
      <description>To test Hypothesis 3, we evaluated the geographical basis of population terminology use and variation in US-specific racial and ethnic categories over time. First, we extracted and parsed all of the address information of authors in our diversity corpus, recoding these data into ISO Alpha-2 country codes. We then examined how often all population terms (i.e. the dictionary of 8,200+ terms) were used from researchers in each country across both the biomedical and diversity samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dictionaries</title>
      <link>/analyses/dictionaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/dictionaries/</guid>
      <description>To conduct our analyses on the growth of diversity in biomedical research, we used natural language processing to examine the rise and fall of terms from 1990-2017. This strategy allows for multiple terms to be collapsed into a general category set. For each hypothsis, we created a unique dictionary of term sets and, in the hope of being fully transparent, we have outlined the process through which we created these dictionaries below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplementary Materials</title>
      <link>/analyses/supplementary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/supplementary/</guid>
      <description>{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;data&#34;:[{&#34;x&#34;:[1990,1991,1992,1993,1994,1995,1996,1997,1998,1999,2000,2001,2002,2003,2004,2005,2006,2007,2008,2009,2010,2011,2012,2013,2014,2015,2016,2017],&#34;y&#34;:[442,451,608,619,690,787,896,1063,1067,1168,1396,1516,1712,1873,2050,2185,2390,2529,2585,2957,3262,3392,3754,4054,4131,4681,4882,4988],&#34;text&#34;:[&#34;year: 1990
diversity: 442
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1991
diversity: 451
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1992
diversity: 608
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1993
diversity: 619
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1994
diversity: 690
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1995
diversity: 787
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1996
diversity: 896
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1997
diversity: 1063
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1998
diversity: 1067
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1999
diversity: 1168
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 2000
diversity: 1396
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 2001
diversity: 1516
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 2002</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>