<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Rise of Diversity and Population Terminology in Biomedical Research</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Rise of Diversity and Population Terminology in Biomedical Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 1</title>
      <link>/results/hypothesis1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/results/hypothesis1/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  Over the past several years, social scientists have noted that the discourse of &amp;quot;diversity&amp;quot; is expanding in use across various organizations (Berrey 2015; Ray 2019). While these authors speak to the discourse of diversity being a mechanism for domininant (white) racial groups in power to pay lip service to racial inequity without addressing these problems through the reallocation of resources, our interest in diversity is to better understand how it is used in biomedical research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 2</title>
      <link>/results/hypothesis2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/results/hypothesis2/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  Next, we wanted to examine the growth of OMB Directive 15 and US Census terms. To test Hypothesis 2, we compiled a dictionary used to catch to the main OMB/US Census terms, including Asian, White, Black, Native American, Pacific Islander, Hispanic/Latinx as well as more general terms like race and ethnicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 3</title>
      <link>/results/hypothesis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/results/hypothesis3/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  Overview While our first set of analyses established that &amp;quot;diversity&amp;quot; is increasing in the biomedical literature, we also wanted to account for how terminology related to population testing has changed over time. For example, Panofsky and Bliss (2017) have found that racial and ethnic terms (including those within the US Census and OMB Directive 15 labeling schema) have been replaced by more general biogeographic terms such continental, national, and directional terminology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }     The Rise of Diversity and Population  Terminology in Biomedical Research Brandon Kramer &amp;amp; Catherine Lee This website was designed to serve as supplement to a paper in progress on the rise of diversity in biomedical research. While the motivation and methods are outlined below, our findings can be found by clicking the Results tab above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }     The Rise of Diversity and Population  Terminology in Biomedical Research Brandon Kramer &amp;amp; Catherine Lee While existing research on race and affirmative action have detailed the growth of diversity projects in education and employment that obfuscate the language of race and racism, the field of science &amp;amp; technology studies have documented scientists persistent attempts to molecularize race in biomedical research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>