<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supplementary Materials</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Supplementary Materials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 1</title>
      <link>/analyses/hypothesis1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/hypothesis1/</guid>
      <description>To test Hypothesis 1, we conducted word frequency analysis to observe (1) variation in raw word counts over time and (2) to analyze variance in word frequency based on the proportion of publications that the term is used in each year. These terms included various diversity-related terms, including aging, ancestry, cultural, diversity, genetic, minority, population, race/ethnicity, sex/gender and sexuality. These analyses were conducted on both the diversity corpus and the more general corpus of biomedical abstracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 2</title>
      <link>/analyses/hypothesis2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/hypothesis2/</guid>
      <description>Next, we return to the diversity corpus to test Hypothesis 2. Here, we examine whether the use of population terminology has grown in biomedical abstracts over the past three decades. To do this, we build on Panofsky and Bliss’s (2017) exploration of how research scientists enact population differences using a polyvocality of terms, including geographic classifications like continents and countries. Drawing from their coding schema, we developed a list of over 2,100 terms that correspond to national, continental, racial, ethnic, and other general population groupings (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 3</title>
      <link>/analyses/hypothesis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/hypothesis3/</guid>
      <description>To test Hypothesis 3, we parsed our dictionary of 2,100 population terms into a set of more nuanced categories. Our main objective is to test Fujimura and Rajagopalan’s (2011) assertion that researchers now use national and continental terms more often than race and ethnicity in their studies. Once again, following Panofsky and Bliss (2017), we looked at the use of continent and country terminology, US-specific terms (corresponding to the US Census and OMB Directive 15 labeling schema), a category of general population terms (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis 4</title>
      <link>/analyses/hypothesis4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/hypothesis4/</guid>
      <description>Finally, to test Hypothesis 4, we evaluated the geographical basis of population terminology use and variation in US-specific racial and ethnic categories over time. We did in two steps. First, we extracted and parsed all of the address information of authors in our diversity corpus, recoding these data into ISO Alpha-2 country codes. We then examined how often all population terms (i.e. our dictionary of 2,100 terms) were used from researchers in each country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Description</title>
      <link>/description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/description/</guid>
      <description>While existing research on race and affirmative action have documented the growth of diversity projects in education and employment, the field of science &amp;amp; technology studies have documented the persistence of scientists to molecularize race in biomedical research. In our paper, we employ computational text analysis to examine quantitative patterns in the use of diversity and population-specific terminology in biomedical research over the course of the past three decades. Drawing from two large samples of scientific abstracts, we document trends in both the raw and proportional usage of diversity and population-specific terminology over the past three decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplementary Materials</title>
      <link>/analyses/supplementary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyses/supplementary/</guid>
      <description>{&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;data&#34;:[{&#34;x&#34;:[1990,1991,1992,1993,1994,1995,1996,1997,1998,1999,2000,2001,2002,2003,2004,2005,2006,2007,2008,2009,2010,2011,2012,2013,2014,2015,2016,2017],&#34;y&#34;:[504,521,725,735,852,1000,1116,1267,1272,1401,1589,1731,1905,2125,2291,2401,2596,2722,2775,3112,3417,3523,3898,4197,4297,4847,5016,5098],&#34;text&#34;:[&#34;year: 1990
diversity: 504
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1991
diversity: 521
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1992
diversity: 725
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1993
diversity: 735
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1994
diversity: 852
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1995
diversity: 1000
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1996
diversity: 1116
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1997
diversity: 1267
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1998
diversity: 1272
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 1999
diversity: 1401
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 2000
diversity: 1589
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 2001
diversity: 1731
colour: #5D8C5D&#34;,&#34;year: 2002</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>